<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Embedded Systems Certification on Envision Certification</title><link>/embedded/</link><description>Recent content in Embedded Systems Certification on Envision Certification</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 23:45:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/embedded/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>LED Audio Sound Level Display VU Meter Analyzer</title><link>/embedded/led-audio-sound-level-display-vu-meter-analyzer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 20:50:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>/embedded/led-audio-sound-level-display-vu-meter-analyzer/</guid><description>Overview/Description For this project you will be building an LED Audio Sound Level Display VU Meter Analyzer or for short a VU-Meter. This device will react to audio intensity (frequency?) and will light up accordingly in an LED bar graph. This exampled involves an ESP-32 S3 and requires you to design a practical PCB for this purpose.
You'll need the following components:
ESP32­S3­MINI­1 (I'll be referring to is as ESP32 for short) Max9814 Microphone A few capacitors A few resistors Two tactile switches of your choosing A USB receptacle of your choosing A linear voltage regulator of your choosing Process This project will challenge your PCB design, soldering, programming, and 3D modeling skills with an emphasis on PCB design.</description></item><item><title>BLYNK Wifi Tutorial</title><link>/embedded/blynk-wifi-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 21:26:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>/embedded/blynk-wifi-tutorial/</guid><description>This is a tutorial for using BLYNK, an online service that is perfect for controlling IOT devices like the NodeMCU. This can give you full control of the microcontroller regardless of where you are as long as you and the microcontroller are connected to the internet.
Signing up Go to the blynk website and make an account
Making a new Project in Blynk software Create new template On the left hand side, navigate to the template page.</description></item><item><title>IR Beam Breaker with a Simple WiFi Web Server (ESP32)</title><link>/embedded/simple-wifi-web-server-with-esp32/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 21:24:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>/embedded/simple-wifi-web-server-with-esp32/</guid><description>Description The IR beam break system can be used for many applications including security and data collecting. Whenever a person or object is detected (when the IR beam is broken) the instance will be logged on the ESP32 alongside the time the instance took place. The ESP32 will also be capable of sending you emails whenever a beam break occurs or after a certain period of time. By connecting to the server via IP address, a second party can see the full log of instances recorded In this project, we will learn how to use IR beam break sensors, create a webserver using the ESP32, attain the current time from an NTP server, and send email notifications using SMTP.</description></item><item><title>SimpleSynth Project</title><link>/embedded/simplesynth-project/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 03:10:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>/embedded/simplesynth-project/</guid><description>The SimpleSynth is a Teensy-based audio synthesizer. We will be building an expansion board for the Teensy, as well as an enclosure for the boards and controls (switches, buttons, potentiometers, etc…) and then programming the synthesizer using the Arduino IDE and the Audio System Design Tool for the Teensy Audio Library. While the final product represented here is fully functional, it is also very expandable, and users are encouraged to explore ways of doing so by adding various effects, controls, displays, etc…</description></item></channel></rss>