<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>HOPFAM Home on Envision Certification</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in HOPFAM Home on Envision Certification</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Project l0ckcr4ck3r</title><link>/mechanical/project-l0ckcr4ck3r/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 05:06:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>/mechanical/project-l0ckcr4ck3r/</guid><description>By MingWei Yeoh
This is not for the faint of heart. This thing takes long and its hard to get right. Only for the advanced and over achievers.
insert gif of the robot doing thing
About the Project This robot is a true creation of the idea many years ago brought on by Samy Kamkar's robot that &amp;quot;utilized&amp;quot; his algorithm for cracking these combination locks. The entire process works on the majority of locks that aren't old and usually ~30 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Simple WiFi Web Server with ESP32</title><link>/embedded/simple-wifi-web-server-with-esp32/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 21:24:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>/embedded/simple-wifi-web-server-with-esp32/</guid><description>The ESP32 is an amazing module that comes with integrated WiFi capabilities and can be programmed using the Arduino IDE.</description></item><item><title>Exporting Gerbers - Altium</title><link>/electrical/exporting-gerbers-altium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 16:41:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/electrical/exporting-gerbers-altium/</guid><description>Once we have a completed PCB layout, we need to order our PCBs. The fastest, cheapest, and most reliable manufacturing house we have found is JLC PCB It typically costs $2 for 5 PCBs, + around $22 for shipping, and they usually take around 5 - 7 days to arrive once ordered. That's quite a deal.
But how do we go from PCB design to the fabrication house? Each software is a little different.</description></item><item><title>Familiarize Yourself</title><link>/electrical/familiarize-yourself/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 20:11:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>/electrical/familiarize-yourself/</guid><description>Microcontrollers:</description></item><item><title>Walking Robot</title><link>/mechanical/walking-robot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 19:16:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>/mechanical/walking-robot/</guid><description>For this project, you will design a robot that walks around using a 4-bar linkage for legs! You will be required to:
Design a working chassis to house all electronic components in SolidWorks. Manufacture and/or source all parts needed (nuts, bolts, motors, microcontrollers, etc.). Create a Motion Study in SolidWorks that theoretically proves your design will work as intended. Assemble the robot and write code to make it run. Brief on 4-bar Linkages 4-bar linkages are a very useful mechanism used in mechanical engineering that consists of four rods connected by pins.</description></item><item><title>SimpleSynth Project</title><link>/embedded/simplesynth-project/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 03:10:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>/embedded/simplesynth-project/</guid><description>The SimpleSynth is a Teensy-based audio synthesizer. We will be building an expansion board for the Teensy, as well as an enclosure for the boards and controls (switches, buttons, potentiometers, etc…) and then programming the synthesizer using the Arduino IDE and the Audio System Design Tool for the Teensy Audio Library. While the final product represented here is fully functional, it is also very expandable, and users are encouraged to explore ways of doing so by adding various effects, controls, displays, etc…</description></item><item><title>Schematic Design</title><link>/electrical/schematic-design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 23:21:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>/electrical/schematic-design/</guid><description>1.1 Introduction
Physical circuits on a board are first built on paper in the form of a schematic diagram. Circuit design typically begins with a schematic, where components are chosen, nets are created, and the flow of signals determined. The PCB is then created by using the schematic as its primary reference. Building the PCB from the schematic and working with the two in tandem not only simplifies PCB layout, but also allows for better error checking, component selection, and overall workflow.</description></item><item><title>Obstacle Avoidance Robot</title><link>/mechanical/obstacle-avoidance-robot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 20:54:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>/mechanical/obstacle-avoidance-robot/</guid><description>By Blake Iwaisako
Description: Build a rover vehicle that drives straight until it encounters an object that it must detect and drive away from (Like a small Roomba!). This project can be made using a microcontroller of your choice, in this example I will use an Arduino Uno combined with an Adafruit motor shield. This document will also be covering the basics of ultrasonic sensors as it is used for detecting objects within a specified distance.</description></item><item><title>Finite Element Analysis: SolidWorks</title><link>/tutorials/finite-element-analysis-solidworks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 18:57:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>/tutorials/finite-element-analysis-solidworks/</guid><description>Finite Element Analysis: SolidWorks
1.1 Quick Introduction: Finite Element Analysis (FEA) is a powerful tool used by engineers to predict how parts and assemblies react to forces: heat, fluid flow, vibration, etc. Computer software such as SolidWorks, FEMAP, ANSYS, and Matlab use numerical analysis to create a general 3D mesh on the surface of the product and calculate stresses based on user-defined materials and forces. Note: Solidworks is not the most precise FEA software to use for engineering purposes, however, it is still accurate and is simple to use.</description></item><item><title>PCB Layout</title><link>/electrical/pcb-layout/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 01:59:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>/electrical/pcb-layout/</guid><description>PCB Layout:
1.1 Introduction:
PCB layout is a necessary part of electronics development. While breadboards and perfboards are fine for prototyping, fabrication and manufacturing for a production run require a fully functional and professional circuit board. There are several options regarding circuit design tools, but we will focus on three common ones: Eagle, KiCAD and Altium. While there are substantial differences between these programs, there are also many topics and practices that are ubiquitous across platforms.</description></item><item><title>Motion Study: SolidWorks</title><link>/tutorials/solidworks-motion-study/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 18:31:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>/tutorials/solidworks-motion-study/</guid><description>Solidworks Motion Study
EnVision Maker Studio
1.1 Introduction: Motion studies are graphical simulations of motion for assembly models. You can use Solidworks mates in an assembly to restrict the motion of components in an assembly when you model motion. Motion studies in Solidworks do not change the properties of an assembly model. Instead, if changes are made to the assembly after the creation of the motion study, the software will automatically update the study and reveal any possible conflicts.</description></item><item><title>wipers</title><link>/electrical/wipers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 18:30:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>/electrical/wipers/</guid><description>test CMS</description></item><item><title>Pcb Design with KiCAD</title><link>/electrical/pcb-design-with-kicad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 18:15:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>/electrical/pcb-design-with-kicad/</guid><description>Test netlifyCMS
In richtext, BOLD
plain</description></item><item><title>3D Printing</title><link>/mechanical/3d-printing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:15:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>/mechanical/3d-printing/</guid><description>Click me!</description></item><item><title>Omni Car Project</title><link>/mechanical/omni-car-project/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:15:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>/mechanical/omni-car-project/</guid><description>About Omni Car Project By: MingWei Yeoh
It's a tank driven car with omni wheels for some sick drifting without the fear of shredding the floor! Combined with a responsive FLYSKY Drone Transmitter, this makes for a fun project!
Challenges CAD The main gripe with the included motors in the kit is that they are a little slow. Thus we will be making a custom 1:2 speed gearbox with OnShape in order to speed up the drive wheels!</description></item><item><title>Slip Ring Project</title><link>/electrical/baby-slip-ring/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:15:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>/electrical/baby-slip-ring/</guid><description>About the Project We will be creating a pcb slip ring that lights up 2 LED lights with a USB C Connector!
Slip rings are devices that allow electrical contacts through rotating bodies.
Usually you would simply buy a slip ring, so the question remains, why reinvent the slip ring if it already exists?
My excuse was that they're expensive. Most especially ones with a through hole in the center :( Slip rings are a good way to practice PCB and CAD design.</description></item><item><title>Search</title><link>/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/search/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>