<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tutorial Links on Envision Certification</title><link>/tutorials/</link><description>Recent content in Tutorial Links on Envision Certification</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 21:24:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Finite Element Analysis: SolidWorks</title><link>/tutorials/finite-element-analysis-solidworks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 18:57:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>/tutorials/finite-element-analysis-solidworks/</guid><description>Finite Element Analysis: SolidWorks
1.1 Quick Introduction: Finite Element Analysis (FEA) is a powerful tool used by engineers to predict how parts and assemblies react to forces: heat, fluid flow, vibration, etc. Computer software such as SolidWorks, FEMAP, ANSYS, and Matlab use numerical analysis to create a general 3D mesh on the surface of the product and calculate stresses based on user-defined materials and forces. Note: Solidworks is not the most precise FEA software to use for engineering purposes, however, it is still accurate and is simple to use.</description></item><item><title>Motion Study: SolidWorks</title><link>/tutorials/solidworks-motion-study/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 18:31:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>/tutorials/solidworks-motion-study/</guid><description>Solidworks Motion Study
EnVision Maker Studio
1.1 Introduction: Motion studies are graphical simulations of motion for assembly models. You can use Solidworks mates in an assembly to restrict the motion of components in an assembly when you model motion. Motion studies in Solidworks do not change the properties of an assembly model. Instead, if changes are made to the assembly after the creation of the motion study, the software will automatically update the study and reveal any possible conflicts.</description></item></channel></rss>