<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mechanical Design and Prototyping Certification on Envision Certification</title><link>/mechanical/</link><description>Recent content in Mechanical Design and Prototyping Certification on Envision Certification</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 22:00:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/mechanical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Project l0ckcr4ck3r</title><link>/mechanical/project-l0ckcr4ck3r/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 05:06:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>/mechanical/project-l0ckcr4ck3r/</guid><description>By MingWei Yeoh
This is not for the faint of heart. This thing takes long and its hard to get right. Only for the advanced and over achievers.
PCB Files found here.
Code found here
Video
About the Project This robot is a true creation of the idea many years ago brought on by Samy Kamkar's robot that &amp;quot;utilized&amp;quot; his algorithm for cracking these combination locks. The entire process works on the majority of locks that aren't old and usually ~40 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Walking Robot</title><link>/mechanical/walking-robot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 19:16:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>/mechanical/walking-robot/</guid><description>For this project, you will design a robot that walks around using a 4-bar linkage for legs! You will be required to:
Design a working chassis to house all electronic components in SolidWorks. Manufacture and/or source all parts needed (nuts, bolts, motors, microcontrollers, etc.). Create a Motion Study in SolidWorks that theoretically proves your design will work as intended. Assemble the robot and write code to make it run. Brief on 4-bar Linkages 4-bar linkages are a very useful mechanism used in mechanical engineering that consists of four rods connected by pins.</description></item><item><title>Obstacle Avoidance Robot</title><link>/mechanical/obstacle-avoidance-robot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 20:54:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>/mechanical/obstacle-avoidance-robot/</guid><description>By Blake Iwaisako
Description: Build a rover vehicle that drives straight until it encounters an object that it must detect and drive away from (Like a small Roomba!). This project can be made using a microcontroller of your choice, in this example I will use an Arduino Uno combined with an Adafruit motor shield. This document will also be covering the basics of ultrasonic sensors as it is used for detecting objects within a specified distance.</description></item><item><title>3D Printing</title><link>/mechanical/3d-printing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:15:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>/mechanical/3d-printing/</guid><description>Click me!</description></item><item><title>Omni Car Project</title><link>/mechanical/omni-car-project/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:15:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>/mechanical/omni-car-project/</guid><description>About Omni Car Project By: MingWei Yeoh
It's a tank driven car with omni wheels for some sick drifting without the fear of shredding the floor! Combined with a responsive FLYSKY Drone Transmitter, this makes for a fun project!
Challenges CAD The main gripe with the included motors in the kit is that they are a little slow. Thus we will be making a custom 1:2 speed gearbox with OnShape in order to speed up the drive wheels!</description></item></channel></rss>