<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Electrical Certification on Envision Certification</title><link>/electrical/</link><description>Recent content in Electrical Certification on Envision Certification</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/electrical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Schematic Design</title><link>/electrical/schematic-design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 23:21:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>/electrical/schematic-design/</guid><description>1.1 Introduction
Physical circuits on a board are first built on paper in the form of a schematic diagram. Circuit design typically begins with a schematic, where components are chosen, nets are created, and the flow of signals determined. The PCB is then created by using the schematic as its primary reference. Building the PCB from the schematic and working with the two in tandem not only simplifies PCB layout, but also allows for better error checking, component selection, and overall workflow.</description></item><item><title>PCB Layout</title><link>/electrical/pcb-layout/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 01:59:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>/electrical/pcb-layout/</guid><description>PCB Layout:
1.1 Introduction:
PCB layout is a necessary part of electronics development. While breadboards and perfboards are fine for prototyping, fabrication and manufacturing for a production run require a fully functional and professional circuit board. There are several options regarding circuit design tools, but we will focus on three common ones: Eagle, KiCAD and Altium. While there are substantial differences between these programs, there are also many topics and practices that are ubiquitous across platforms.</description></item><item><title>wipers</title><link>/electrical/wipers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 18:30:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>/electrical/wipers/</guid><description>test CMS</description></item><item><title>Pcb Design with KiCAD</title><link>/electrical/pcb-design-with-kicad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 18:15:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>/electrical/pcb-design-with-kicad/</guid><description>Test netlifyCMS
In richtext, BOLD
plain</description></item><item><title>PCB Slip Ring Project</title><link>/electrical/baby-slip-ring/documentation/instructions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:15:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>/electrical/baby-slip-ring/documentation/instructions/</guid><description>About the Project We will be creating a pcb slip ring that lights up 2 LED lights with a USB C Connector!
Slip rings are devices that allow electrical contacts through rotating bodies. ![[slipring.gif|350]]
![[cadslipring.gif]] Usually you would buy things like this, so the question remains, why reinvent the slip ring if it already exists?
My excuse was that they're expensive. Over 200$ if you need one with a through hole in the center :(</description></item></channel></rss>